{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What does GMAW stand for?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Gas Magnetic arc welding",
        "b": "Gas Metal arc welding",
        "c": "Gas Mixed arc welding",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
 {
      "question": "Which of the following metal transfer mode can occur during MIG welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Globular transfer",
        "b": "Short Circuit Transfer",
        "c": "Spray transfer",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "d":"You are right"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the main advantage of GMAW welding over other GTAW?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "high metal deposition",
        "b": "Lower cost",
        "c": "Better penetration",
        "d": "All of the above"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "d":"You are right"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the use of the shielding gas in GMAW welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Prevent oxidation",
        "b": "Increase the heat of the weld",
        "c": "Make the weld stronger",
        "d": "Cool the weld"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "Which of the following shielding gases is typically used to achieve shallower penetration in GMAW welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Argon",
        "b": "Carbon dioxide ",
        "c": "Helium",
        "d": "Oxygen"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the effect of using a higher voltage in MIG welding?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Shorter weld bead",
        "b": "Larger weld bead",
        "c": "Better penetration",
        "d": "Higher strength of the weld"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "How does using a larger diameter wire affect the MIG weld?",
      "answers":{ 
        "a": "Improves penetration",
        "b": "Decreases penetration",
        "c": "Makes the weld stronger",
        "d": "No effect on the weld"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
{
      "question": "What is the effect of using a lower amperage in MIG welding?",
      "answers":{ 
        "a": "Shorter weld bead",
        "b": "Larger weld bead",
        "c": "Better penetration",
        "d": "Decreased strength of the weld"
      },
      "explanations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "For consistent arc length which type of power source is used by GMAW process?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Constant Current power source",
        "b": "Constant voltage power source",
        "c": "Both a & b",
        "d": "none of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
       "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which of the following metal transfer mode metal transfer in the form of large droplets to the workpiece",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Spray Transfer",
        "b": "Short circuiting transfer",
        "c": "Globular transfer",
        "d": "Pulsed arc transfer"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },

{
      "question": "Which of the following shielding gases are used for the welding of various carbon steels?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Helium",
        "b": "Nitrogen",
        "c": "Argon/CO2",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explanations": {
       "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
]
}





